Preliminary Guide to the Team Detroit Office Records, 2006-2009 RL.01281
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Team Detroit Office records
2006-2009
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Team Detroit
RL.01281
4 Linear Feet
Team Detroit is an umbrella organization that includes J. Walter Thompson and a number of other sister advertising agencies. It consolidates all of the ad agencies that work for the Ford Motor Company in Detroit. The accession (2009-0194) (1200 items; 4 lin. ft.; dated 2006-2009) includes marketing plans, sample advertisements and mailings, and launch details for a variety of Ford, Lincoln, Mercury, and Cadillac vehicles between 2006 and 2008. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
1200 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted for 15 years. Contact Research Services for more information.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Team Detroit Office Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2009.
Biographical and Historical Note
Team Detroit is an umbrella organization that includes J. Walter Thompson and a number of other sister advertising agencies who work for the Ford Motor Company in Detroit.
Collection Overview
Accession (2009-0194) (1200 items; 4 lin. ft.; dated 2006-2009) includes marketing plans, sample advertisements and mailings, and launch details for a variety of Ford, Lincoln, Mercury, and Cadillac vehicles between 2006 and 2008.
Advertising -- Automobiles -- United States; Detroit (Mich.); Automobiles -- Marketing; Advertising agencies -- History; J. Walter Thompson Company; Team Detroit; Team Detroit; Ford Motor Company
- Accession (2009-0194), 2006-2009, 3 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Accession (2009-0194) (1200 items; 4 lin. ft.; dated 2006-2009) includes marketing plans, sample advertisements and mailings, and launch details for a variety of Ford, Lincoln, Mercury, and Cadillac vehicles between 2006 and 2008.
  Arrangement note
  This collection has not been processed; materials have been reboxed with folder titles listed below.
  - Ford Motor Company Statement Integration (Box 1)
  - Digital Segmentation with Purpose, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Lincoln Savor the Dream, 2007 (Box 1)
  - LCM email curriculum, April 2007 (Box 1)
  - MSN Control Room L-M, 2007 (Box 1)
  - M. Richards Chairman meeting, Sept. 2007 (Box 1)
  - LM email plan, 2007 (Box 1)
  - 2007 Lincoln Navigator brief (Box 1)
  - 2008 Mercury Mariner launch (Box 1)
  - Lincoln Communication Strategy, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Mercury - American Legion, 2006 (Box 1)
  - Lincoln Direct Plans, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Mercury Direct Plan, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Non-cash incentive task force (Box 1)
  - SOS/Live Earth event (Box 1)
  - Lexus Comp. review (Box 1)
  - Lexus benchmarking (Box 1)
  - Cadillac Influencer program (Box 1)
  - 2008 Focus revival (Box 1)
  - Project ICE NDAs (Box 1)
  - ICE (Box 1)
  - Loyalty data (Box 1)
  - Owner privilege, business case (Box 1)
  - House party (Box 1)
  - Ford Motor credit roadmap, 2006 (Box 1)
  - Ford brand strategy, 2006 (Box 1)
  - Digital Media Strategy, 2006 (Box 1)
  - Email (owner) recruitment, Oct. 2006 (Box 1)
  - Added Value review team (Box 1)
  - Time Inc.-Bolt Performance Awards, Oct. 2006 (Box 1)
  - Women's strategy - Fusion (Box 1)
  - Flash stores (Box 1)
  - Women's, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Ford car enthusiast (Box 1)
  - Women's, 2006 (Box 1)
  - 2007 Edge launch (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Planning, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Women's, 2006 (Box 1)
  - 2008 Mercury Sable launch reference binder (Box 1)
  - Lincoln Savor the Dream 2007 tour recap binder (Box 1)
  - 2008 F/M Guidebook Exposure event binder (Box 1)
  - Mariner RFP (Box 2)
  - JD Power Award, June 2007 (Box 2)
  - 2008 Mercury Sable launch (Box 2)
  - Lincoln Loyalty (3) (Box 2)
  - Comm. planning process (Box 2)
  - Sync (Box 2)
  - Digital Objectives and Strategies, 2007 (Box 2)
  - Lease terminations (Box 2)
  - LMDA Navigator Integrated Retail Marketing Program, Mar. 2007 (Box 2)
  - Mercury/Sirius 60-Day, 2007 (Box 2)
  - Outside Magazine-Stay 30 Forever tour, 2007 (Box 2)
  - Sample mailings and advertisements for Ford, Lincoln, and Mercury vehicles (Box 2)
  - Oversize sample mailings and advertisements for Ford, Lincoln, Cadillac, and Mercury vehicles (Box 3)